Javier Ubillos

Product Lead, Tech lead

CPO, CTO, Founder

A highly driven, no-ego, product and technology leader with broad experience across domains and company sizes.

I co-founded NudgeLabs, a Y-Combinator (W22) startup, was a part of Spotifys highest growth phase and am helping startups, scaleups and enterprises with the entire range from finding product-to-market-fit to leading teams towards serving their customers and stakeholders with a product-mindset.

What's the shortest path to product-to-market-fit? Once it is found, how do we, in the most pragmatic way, deliver that product and scale?

EXPERIENCE

IKEA (contractor)— *Product development mentor*

MARS 2023 - PRESENT

Teaching product mindset for infrastructure teams and actively driving a product team in a Product Owner capacityTeaching product mindset for infrastructure teams and actively driving a product team in a Product Owner capacity

Deploying a cost effective, IKEA-scale Observabilty platform, applying product mindset

NudgeLabs (YC W22)— CPO/CTO

APRIL 2021 - Jan 2023

Combining Biodata & CBT to optimize users efforts to improve their wellbeing. Product and Technology lead. Covering the stretch from idea, user-research to technology choice and deploying prototypes and production ready apps to users..

Looklet — CTO

JANUARY 2018 - AUGUST 2021

Photography and technology solution for fashion e-commerce imagery.

Leading the development Lookets platform and coaching the product team on best practices. Looklet ties together physical photography, crowdsource like retouch scalability, and machine-learning technologies.

Spotify— *Product Owner*

JULY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

EDUCATION

Mälardalen University — MSc Computer Science

2002 - 2008

Computer Science

+46 (0)76 764 75 88 javier@ubillos.org

SKILLS

Product development
User research
Prototyping
Product-to-market-fit
MVP

Engineering leadership
Agile development
Technology choices
Outsourcing/insourcing

Investor relations

LINKS

Github:

https://github.com/jav

Blog:

https://jav.github.io/

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/
in/javierubillos/

Academic publications: https://t.ly/oto_4

For more a more detailed CV Please visit my LinkedIn profile.

https://www.linkedin.com/
in/iavierubillos/